The loverliest motion picture of them all!
My Fair Lady is a comedy, romance film directed by George Cukor.
A snobbish phonetics professor agrees to a wager that he can take a
flower girl and make her presentable in high society.
Eliza Doolittle, played by Audrey Hepburn.
Professor Henry Higgins, played by Rex Harrison.
Alfred P. Doolittle, played by Stanley Holloway.
Colonel Hugh Pickering, played by Wilfrid Hyde-White.
Mrs. Higgins, played by Gladys Cooper.
Freddy Eynsford-Hill, played by Jeremy Brett.
My Fair Lady is a 1964 American musical comedy drama film adapted from the 1956 Lerner and
Loewe stage musical based on George Bernard Shaw's 1913 stage play Pygmalion.
With a screenplay by Alan Jay Lerner and directed by George Cukor, the film depicts a poor Cockney flower-seller named Eliza Doolittle who overhears a phonetics professor, Henry Higgins, as he
casually wagers that he could teach her to speak English so well she could pass for a duchess in Edwardian London or better yet, from Eliza's viewpoint, secure employment in a flower store.
The film stars Audrey Hepburn as Eliza Doolittle—replacing Julie Andrews from the stage musical—and Rex Harrison as Henry
Higgins—reprising his role from the stage musical—with Stanley Holloway, Gladys Cooper and Wilfrid Hyde-White in supporting roles.
A critical and commercial success, it became the second-highest-grossing film of 1964 (after Mary
Poppins) and won eight Academy Awards, including Best Picture, Best Director and Best Actor.
American Film Institute included the film as #91 in its 1998 AFI's 100 Years...100 Movies, as #12 in its
2002 AFI's 100 Years...100 Passions, and as #8 in its 2006 AFI's Greatest Movie Musicals.
In 2018, the film was selected for preservation in the United States National Film Registry by the
Library of Congress as being "culturally, historically, or aesthetically significant."
The film explores themes of transformation,
musical, flower girl, colonel, suitor.
The tone is lighthearted and emotional.